<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>allyson kate</title>
    <description>A simple, beautiful theme for Jekyll that emphasizes content rather than aesthetic fluff.</description>
    <link>https://allysonkate.github.io//</link>
    <atom:link href="https://allysonkate.github.io//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Online Communities</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/neopets.png&quot; alt=&quot;neopets banner&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s one thing I’ve known about myself ever since I was introduced to the internet itself, and that’s how important online communities are to me. If you tried to visualize that, it would resemble an embarrassing, emotional overlapping timeline from everything from Neopets, YA novel forums, to (a much more mature?) YouTube and Twitter. Each had me just as passionate and committed as the last.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While many of these communities still hold true in my daily life, the recent entrance of one in 2015 has fueled me in so many ways that I simply must speak on the value it of my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The beauty of Slack for me lies in the diversity in content, community, and discussion that you have the opportunity to be welcome and a part of, regardless of your status.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I belong to a Slack community about the future of podcasting, web friends in Chicago, UX designers, and women with careers in product. The talent and intelligence I’m surrounded everyday within the Slack communities is incredible, humbling, and one of the purest forms of positive online communities today.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2016 00:43:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://allysonkate.github.io//words/2016/01/05/slack/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://allysonkate.github.io//words/2016/01/05/slack/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Second City</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In January of 2014, I was hired at The Second City, a world-renowned comedy club, theatre and school of improvisation,  as an in-house design intern. Since then, I have grown from intern, to Jr. Designer, to Designer, to my current title, Sr. Designer on a team of 5.  As part of a small design team in a multi-fasicted company, I’ve been able to have a hand in almost every department across the globe and cater my position to areas I’ve seen need, potential, and had personal interest. A few of my favorite projects and products are discussed below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;secondcitycom&quot;&gt;secondcity.com&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a grew within the company, I showed interest in the redesign of the website on Wordpress, a project that had been contracted out before I was hired. I saw a great need for project management, UX knowledge, and communication within our company regarding this redesign. Along with the VP of New Media at The Second City, I became a point person for the project. I started researching client needs, wireframing pages, helping with quality control &amp;amp; page speed, and discussing our user experience needs and information architecture with the contractor. Featured above are a few of the pages I hand in redesigning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;sctvcom&quot;&gt;sctv.com&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our producer in Toronto expressed the need for a website for&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-second-city-network&quot;&gt;The Second City Network&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another project I expressed early interest in was our YouTube channel, SecondCityNetwork. I helped rebrand and create a variety of end cards&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;marketing-campaigns&quot;&gt;Marketing Campaigns&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2015 01:42:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://allysonkate.github.io//work/2015/10/31/the-second-city/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://allysonkate.github.io//work/2015/10/31/the-second-city/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>She Hacks Tumblr</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I had the privilege of attending an all female hackathon at Cleverbridge in Chicago to get young girls interested in STEM. My group set out to build an unitimidating playground that teaches young girls how to customize their Tumblr theme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Tumblr remains the only widely used social platform that lets you customize the code, unlike years ago when many of us became familiar with code by customizing Neopets or Myspace layouts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And there it was. We had our passion product. We were going to build not just a tutorial, but a Tumblr playground. A low-steaks environment to learn, mess up, add personality, and instantly see the effects of &lt;em&gt;your&lt;/em&gt; code on &lt;em&gt;your&lt;/em&gt; site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to the generous social reach of one of our group members, we were able to do some quick field research regarding interest in the product and features they’d like to see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/AnnaRussett&quot;&gt;@AnnaRussett&lt;/a&gt; yes &amp;amp; no :/ im still learning how to code&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; toni-gayle (@dumbchie) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/dumbchie/status/655177118494687232&quot;&gt;October 17, 2015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/AnnaRussett&quot;&gt;@AnnaRussett&lt;/a&gt; I&amp;#39;ve copy and pasted themes but I&amp;#39;ve never made my own it seems too hard 😂&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Lil-E (@lelilliann) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/lelilliann/status/655176946972798980&quot;&gt;October 17, 2015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/AnnaRussett&quot;&gt;@AnnaRussett&lt;/a&gt; music!! I don&amp;#39;t know how to put a player on there.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; kris (@kristenlongg) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/kristenlongg/status/655185262553657344&quot;&gt;October 17, 2015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;together-we-spent-our-saturday-creating-she-hacks-tumblr&quot;&gt;Together, we spent our Saturday creating She Hacks Tumblr.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Built using HTML, CSS, and Javascript, our team built a bare bones Tumblr theme using minimal code. I was responsible for the UI &amp;amp; UX and partnered up for the HTML &amp;amp; CSS. The biggest challenge during any hackathon is always time, but we were able to develop the first few tutorial steps and push live for the demo on &lt;a href=&quot;http://shehacks.tumblr.com/&quot; title=&quot;She Hacks Tumblr&quot;&gt;shehacks.tumblr.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;after-8-hours-of-coding-we-presented-in-front-of-a-panel-of-judges-and-won-the-quit-your-day-job-award-although-we-do-plan-on-developing-the-product-further-i-cant-say-any-of-us-have-taken-that-award-literally-yet-x2727&quot;&gt;After 8 hours of coding, we presented in front of a panel of judges and won the “Quit Your Day Job” Award. Although we do plan on developing the product further, I can’t say any of us have taken that award literally yet. ✧&lt;/h4&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2015 01:42:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://allysonkate.github.io//work/2015/10/31/she-hacks-tumblr/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://allysonkate.github.io//work/2015/10/31/she-hacks-tumblr/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Big Frame/Youtube</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Since 2013, I’ve been working with and as talent at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bigfra.me/&quot; title=&quot;Big Frame&quot;&gt;Big Frame&lt;/a&gt;, a multi-channel YouTube network in Los Angeles. Youtube has been a huge part of my life since 2007, which I talk about a little more &lt;a href=&quot;https://allysonkate.github.io/word/2015/10/05/youtube%203/&quot; title=&quot;What Youtube Means to Me&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. In 2013 I signed with Big Frame for two years as a content creator, producing videos on my personal channel in conjunction with a all-female vertical network initiative. As it became clearer to me that I didn’t want to pursue YouTube as a career, I began fostering a design freelance relationship with Big Frame (now owned by DreamWorks/AwesomenessTV), which has now grown beyond my contract as talent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few of the YouTubers I’ve worked with include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sarah Penna &lt;em&gt;(Big Frame co-founder, now with AwesomenessTV)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Joe Penna &lt;em&gt;(&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/user/MysteryGuitarMan&quot; title=&quot;MysteryGuitarMan&quot;&gt;MysteryGuitarMan&lt;/a&gt; → 2.85 mil)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jimmy Tatro &lt;em&gt;(&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/user/lifeaccordingtojimmy&quot; title=&quot;LifeAccordingToJimmy&quot;&gt;LifeAccordingToJimmy&lt;/a&gt; → 2.5 mil)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rebecca Black &lt;em&gt;(&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/user/rebecca&quot; title=&quot;rebecca&quot;&gt;rebecca&lt;/a&gt; → 1.25 mil)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jenn McAllister &lt;em&gt;(&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/user/jennxpenn&quot; title=&quot;jennxpenn&quot;&gt;jennxpenn&lt;/a&gt; → 2.25 mil)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Arden Rose &lt;em&gt;(&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/user/ARose186&quot; title=&quot;rebecca&quot;&gt;ARose186&lt;/a&gt;  → 1.3 mil)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2015 01:42:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://allysonkate.github.io//work/2015/10/31/big-frame/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://allysonkate.github.io//work/2015/10/31/big-frame/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The YouTube Thing</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/YouTube_Screenshot.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Youtube Self&quot; /&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When asked about my involvement with YouTube, I always seem to begin with “Well, it started as a hobby…” In high school I would come home from school and watch my favorite vloggers on YouTube. In 2016, this sounds relatively commonplace. In 2007, this wasn’t something you said to people without accepting the fact that you would have to explain what you just said for a good five minutes and still be met with confusion and sarcastic comments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through the years, I watched these people grow up, go through struggles, start college, get into relationships and ultimately regret talking telling the internet about their relationships. No production value concerns, no brand sponsorships, no such thing as “YouTube Stars.” I was extremely passionate about YouTube as a online community platform, and I wanted in. These people understood me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In 2007 YouTube was something special, and I was quickly becoming an introvert IRL simply because no one could understand what the hell I was passionate about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Video responses were the heart and soul of the community, so that’s usually how you got your in. People could put a face to a username. From there, it kind of just snowballed. We were just friends with a cool thing in common. Soon my Friday nights were spent on BlogTV streams and skype was a daily fixture in my life. Gifs starting happening. I was doing collabs left and right. In 2013 I asked people to post a 10 second video giving a pun, calling it “Pun Run 2k13.” There were 40 video responses. I signed with multi-channel network, Big Frame, for two years before I slowly made making videos much less of a priority and decided I wasn’t going to play the YouTube algorithm game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/VidCon_2013a.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;VidCon&quot; /&gt;&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;em&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/VidCon_2013b.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;VidCon&quot; /&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s 2016 and things are insanely different. Insanely different. But that’s okay. To be living through a period of time where we can reflect and watch the rise and fall of online communities, social platforms, and brand adoption… that’s cool as heck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven’t made a video in well over a year now, but I still consider myself a YouTuber. I still go to Anaheim for VidCon, the YouTube convention John and Hank Green started in 2010. Several of my closest friends originated from my YouTube friendships and YouTube provided/aided in most if not all of my design jobs since then (not to mention couches all over the world.) Algorithms, fangirls, brand sponsorships aside, there remains many small but mighty YouTube communities out of the spotlight. The ones using it as a creative outlet or a platform for discussion, that’s where the true value lies. Is there money there? Maybe not. But authentic relationships and meaningful discussion? Absolutely. That’s what YouTube meant to me. That’s where my passion lies: in the cultivation and preservation of those communities. I’d love to talk your ear off about it over coffee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/NerdCon_2015_001.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;NerdCon&quot; /&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I’m still asking myself the same question I was in 2007, “What does YouTube mean to me?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The YouTube community was and is home. I have a feeling this will always remain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;see-you-at-vidcon-nerds&quot;&gt;See you at VidCon, nerds.&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2015 01:42:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://allysonkate.github.io//words/2015/10/05/youtube%202/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://allysonkate.github.io//words/2015/10/05/youtube%202/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>nerdcon stories</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A couple years ago, one of the women in media I admire most, Margaret Kramer, said&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;see-you-at-vidcon-nerds&quot;&gt;See you at VidCon, nerds.&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2015 01:42:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://allysonkate.github.io//2015/10/05/nerdcon-stories/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://allysonkate.github.io//2015/10/05/nerdcon-stories/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Don&#39;t Read The Ipsum</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In 2015 I had the absolute pleasure to be accepted to participate in Chicago’s first &lt;a href=&quot;http://comedyhackday.com&quot; title=&quot;Comedy Hack Day&quot;&gt;Comedy Hack Day&lt;/a&gt;, a hackathon started by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cultivatedwit.com/&quot; title=&quot;Cultivated Wit&quot;&gt;Cultivated Wit&lt;/a&gt; in SF. Built using HTML, CSS, Javascript, I was responsible for the UI &amp;amp; UX and partnered up for the HTML &amp;amp; CSS. By far one of the most incredible weekends of the year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Logo and illustrations by: Subi Shah&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2015 01:42:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://allysonkate.github.io//work/2015/10/02/ipsum-click/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://allysonkate.github.io//work/2015/10/02/ipsum-click/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Echo Magazine</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In the spring of 2013 I served as Art Director over a team of 30 designers and writers for the Summer/Fall 2013 issue circulating 30,000 copies in the Greater Chicago area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/echocover.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;cover&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/hiddentruths1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;page 1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;em&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/hiddentruths2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;page 2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2015 01:42:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://allysonkate.github.io//work/2015/10/02/echo/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://allysonkate.github.io//work/2015/10/02/echo/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
